everything5pounds.com 2019-05-10

# Privacy & Cookies | E5P

## PRIVACY POLICY

15th May 2018

Fiver London Ltd ( **"We"** or **"Us"** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This privacy policy together with our [Sale Terms and Conditions,](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/terms-conditions) (the "Terms") and any other documents referred to in the Terms sets out the basis on which any personal information We collect from you (the “user” or “customer”), or that you provide to Us, will be processed by Us. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information and how We will treat it. 

For the purposes of applicable data protection laws, including the EU General Data Protection Regulation, as amended and supplemented (the “Data Protection Laws”), the “controller” of personal information collected through [www.everything5pounds.com ](https://www.everything5pounds.com/) (the “Website”) is Fiver London Ltd, a company incorporated and registered in England with company number 09229268, whose registered address is 54-56 Camden Lock Place, London, NW1 8AF.

1\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

#### When you create an account

If you create an account with Us, We will collect information about you including your name, phone number, email address, age and gender. You may provide this information to Us directly through forms on the Website, or by signing in to your account with a third party such as Facebook, Google or Twitter (each referred to as a “Third Party Platform”) (see “Personal Information We May Collect from Third Parties” below).

We will use the personal information that We collect about you to:

  * create and maintain your account with Us;
  * carry out our obligations arising from any agreements entered into between you and Us;
  * respond to your customer service requests and support needs efficiently;
  * provide you, or permit selected Third Party Service Providers (see **“Personal Information We May Collect from Third Parties”** below) to provide you, with information about goods or services We feel may interest you;
  * notify you about changes to our service or our products; 
  * comply with any legal obligations to which We are subject, and to protect and defend our rights and interests.

#### When you place an order with Us (online account holders)

If you place an order with Us, We will collect information about you including your name, phone number, email address, mailing address and payment details.

We will use the information We collect about you to:

  * communicate with you about your order;
  * handle and process your order;
  * deliver products to you;
  * communicate with relevant suppliers including, for example, courier services;
  * process payments;
  * update our records and details of your account with Us;
  * comply with any legal obligations to which We are subject, and to protect and defend our rights and interests.

#### When you check out as a guest

If you check out as a guest, We will collect information from you including your name, phone number, email address, mailing address and payment details. 

We will use this information to:

  * communicate with you about your order;
  * handle and process your order;
  * deliver the products to you;
  * communicate with relevant suppliers;
  * process payments;
  * update our records;
  * comply with any legal obligations to which We are subject, and to protect and defend our rights and interests.

#### When you sign up to receive emails from Us

If you sign up to receive emails from Us, We will collect your name and email address. We will use this information to send you emails about products and services We think you may be interested in, updates about Us and/or the Website and to notify you of any changes about Our service. 

#### When you contact Us

If you contact Us by telephone, email, post or using any other function offered by the Website, We will collect any information that you provide to Us. 

We will use this information to respond to review, investigate and respond to your questions or comments as necessary. Please note that We may record telephone calls made to Us. 

#### Shopping basket reminder emails

If you have placed items in your shopping basket but not checked out, we may email you to remind you so you can complete your purchase (while stocks last). 

2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM THIRD PARTIES

#### Third Party Platforms and Service Providers

When you use or access the Website by or through a Third Party Platform such as Facebook, Google or Twitter, you allow Us to access and/or collect information from the Third Party Platform (for example, your Facebook account) or via any cookies placed on your device by a Third Party Platform, as permitted by the terms of the agreement and depending on your privacy setting on the Third Party Platform. The information we collect from a Third Party Platform may include your name, gender, age and email address. 

We also work closely with third party service providers including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, advertising networks, analytics providers and search information providers ( **“Third Party Service Providers”** ). We may receive information about you from Third Party Service Providers and We may share some of the information We collect from you with Third Party Service Providers (see **“Disclosure of Your Information”** below). 

3\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE AUTOMATICALLY COLLECT

When you use the Website, we will automatically collect information including:

  * technical information, such as the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; and
  * information about your visit, including: 
    * the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from the Website (including date and time); 
    * products you viewed or searched for; 
    * products you place in your shopping basket but have not purchased; 
    * page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs); and 
    * methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number. 

4\. OUR LEGAL BASIS FOR COLLECTING AND USING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

#### Entering into and performing a contract with you

If you create an account or place an order with Us, our legal basis for processing your personal information is that it is necessary for the performance of the agreement between you and Us.

#### Our legitimate business interests

If you contact Us, sign up to receive emails from Us, or simply browse the Website, our legal basis for processing your personal information is that we have a legitimate interest in administering and monitoring the Website, for analysis and research by Our group, promoting our business and responding to queries.

5\. MARKETING

If you sign up to receive marketing messages from Us, or buy goods from Us, we will contact you from time to time with information about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. We may base these messages on pages you have viewed on the Website. You can opt out of receiving further marketing messages at any time by clicking the **“Unsubscribe”** link in any email you receive from Us, or by visiting **“My Subscriptions”** in your account (if you have created one). For SMS messages, reply with “STOP”. For postal marketing, please use the [Contact Us](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/contact-us) form or write to us at “Stop Marketing”, Everything5Pounds, 54-56 Camden Lock Place, London, NW1 8AF. 

6\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which includes Our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, from time to time (Our **“group”** ). 

We may share your personal information and information about the orders that you place with the suppliers of the products showcased on the Website for which you have submitted an order or enquiry (the “Merchants”). Those Merchants may use your information in the same way as We use your information (as described above), in particular, to dispatch your order.

We may share your information with selected third parties including:

  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract We enter into with them and/or you.
  * Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We may provide these third parties with aggregate information to help them reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in SW1). We may also make use of the personal information We have collected from you to enable Us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to the target audience they are trying to reach.
  * Analytics and search engine providers including Google and Facebook that assist Us in the improvement and optimization of the Website.
  * Third party service providers to help Us operate our business, the Website or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that We sell or buy any business or assets, in which case We may disclose your personal information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If We or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal information held by Us about Our customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If We are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply the [Terms](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/terms-conditions) and other agreements; or to protect our rights, property, or safety, or those of Our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection.

We do not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others.

7\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

The personal information that We collect from you will be transmitted to third parties located in countries outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) including the United States. If you would like more information about how your personal information is transferred, and the safeguards applied, please use the [Contact Us](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/contact-us) form. 

8\. RETENTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

The period for which We will retain your personal information will vary depending on the purposes it was collected for, as well as the requirements of any applicable law or regulation. 

For example, if you order a product on the Website, We will store your personal information and details about your order for as long as is necessary to comply with applicable tax legislation, and for the period for which you or We could bring legal proceedings in relation to your order. 

9\. YOUR RIGHTS

You may have certain rights in relation to the personal information We collect about you. These may include the right to request access to the data We hold about you, or to obtain a copy of the personal information in machine readable format, to request that it is erased or that any inaccurate personal information is rectified. You may also have the right to ask Us to restrict how we process your personal information or to withdraw your consent to how We process your personal information. Please use the [Contact Us](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/contact-us) form if you would like to make a request. 

You also have the right to complain about the use of your personal data to the Supervisory Authority, which in the UK is the [Information Commissioner’s Office.](https://ico.org.uk/)

10\. THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partners, affiliates, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content on these websites and We are not responsible for the practices employed by them. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy and customer support policies and We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please carefully check these policies before you submit any personal information to these websites. 

11\. CHANGES TO OUR POLICY

This policy will be reviewed from time to time to take account of changes to Our operations and practices. If We make changes, We will notify you by revising the date at the top of this policy, and if the changes are significant, We may provide you with additional notice, such as adding a statement to the homepage of the Website or sending you an email with the update. Any personal information held will be governed by Our most current policy. 

12\. CONTACT US

If you have any questions or requests regarding this privacy policy, the practices of the Website or your dealings with the Website, please use the [Contact Us](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/contact-us) form. 

## COOKIE POLICY

Introduction

This Cookies Policy is issued by Fiver London Limited (referred to as "we", "us", "our" or "Fiver" in this Cookies Policy).

This policy applies to our use of "cookies" in connection with our website, [www.everything5pounds.com ](https://www.everything5pounds.com/) ("Website").

We use cookies on our Website to help make your visits more effective so we'd like to explain more about how and why we use them. By continuing to browse our Website without adjusting your browser settings to block cookies (for information about how to do this please see below), you are agreeing to our use of cookies. 

What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files that may be stored on your computer (or other internet enabled devices, such as a smartphone or tablet) when you visit a website. They help websites remember information about your visit, like your country, language and other settings. They can also help make your next visit easier.

We use Cookies to help you efficiently browse our Website and to save you time by not having to re-enter your details each time you visit. Cookies allow us to provide you with information and show you content relevant to you. We also use Cookies to analyse how our customers interact with our Website so we can improve the customer journey. 

How we use cookies

The cookies used on this website are either set by Fiver or by its third party partners.

Cookies used on this website fall into the following categories: 

  1. Strictly Necessary
  2. Performance
  3. Functionality
  4. Targeting

Some of these are "session cookies", which stay in place only for the duration of your visit to our Website and are deleted at the end of your browsing session. Others are "persistent cookies", which remain on your device for a period of time after you have left the website. 

#### (1) Strictly Necessary Cookies.

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Website and use its features. If you remove or disable these Cookies, we cannot guarantee that you will be able to use our Website or benefit from all our security features.

These Cookies contain a unique reference number which, for example, helps us to:

  * identify you as logged in to secure parts of our Website for the duration of your visit;
  * remember information you have previously entered to complete a form on our Website.

#### (2) Performance Cookies

Performance Cookies collect information about how visitors use our Website. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Website and are used to, for example:

  * analyse how visitors use our Website;
  * record any errors that occur;
  * test different designs of our Website; and
  * measure the effectiveness of our advertising.

Performance Cookies don't collect any information that could identify you.

#### (3) Functionality cookies

These Cookies are used to provide services or to remember choices you make so we can personalise our content for you (for example, by remembering your choice of language or region). We use this information to customise your experience of our Website to meet your preferences for content layout, text size etc.

You can manage these Cookies using your browser settings, however if you block them we may not be able to offer you certain services that you have chosen. 

#### (4) Targeting Cookies

These Cookies record the fact that you have visited our Website, including which web pages you have accessed, which device you have accessed them from and which links you have followed. 

We may use this information, for example:

  * for fraud and website abuse detection purposes, including detecting players who have abused bonus schemes or other promotions, or engaged in arbitrage betting;
  * to deliver online content and marketing (e.g. via email) tailored to your interests, or online experiences; and
  * for providing advertising agencies with information about your visit so that they can show you relevant adverts online.

Please note that any direct communications will be conducted in line with our Privacy Policy and any preferences you have provided regarding receipt of direct marketing communications.

You can manage these Cookies using your browser settings, however, if you block them, we may not be able to offer you certain functionality within the Website. 

More specifically, we may use the following cookies on our websites:

Cookie | Third Party Provider | Category of Cookie | Description of what Cookie does / Purpose | Duration of cookie | Further information  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
JSESSIONID | Fiver London LTD | Strictly Necessary Cookies | Record server session ID variables ( session ID) | 1 Year | Blocking this cookie prevents usage of the online shop  
ROUTEID, acceleratorSecureGUID | Fiver London LTD | Functionality | Record server related variables (node serving the content, session ID, secure session token) | Expires when browsing session ends |   
SearchCategoryCode; SearchPage; SearchQuery; | Fiver London LTD | Functionality | Serve our search engine functionality | Expires when browsing session ends |   
Everything5pounds-cart | Fiver London LTD | Functionality | Save coded cart ID | Persistent |   
splitVarSession, user_type_ck | Fiver London LTD | Functionality | Internal AB testing variable | 1 hour |   
_bron_bae; _bron_bas; _bron_bar; _bron_bav; | Bronto (Oracle) | Targeting | We use Bronto (Oracle) as email marketing tool. These cookies collect information in order to help personalize email marketing campaigns. Some cookies collect encoded contact email address.  | 1 Year, except _bron_bav, which expires within 24 hours.  |  <https://help.bronto.com/bmp/concept/c_bmp_data_retention_policy.html> <https://help.bronto.com/bmp/reference/r_bmp_legal_bronto_cookies_about.html>  
_pk_id.XX, _pk_ref.XX, _pk.ses.XX | Piwik -Open Source Tracking Tool | Performance | Create user ID and session ID for internal traffic measure | 30 minutes to 1 year |   
Adoric_uniq_day_id,  | Adoric -Popup tool | Targeting |  | Expire when session ends, up to |   
_ga, _gat_XX, _gid | Google Inc | Targeting / Performance | We use Google Analytics to help analyse and evaluate your use of the website and compile reports for us on activity on the website. These cookies help us to record the length of individual sessions on our website, the referral method for visitors to our website and the number of unique visitors to our website.  | Some expire within 1 minute, 1 day, or Persistent | For more information, including details of how to block these cookies specifically, please see <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en>  
cd_user_id | Cooladata | Performance | Record encoded user ID to serve internal tracking tool for performance analysis. | 1 year |   
2c.cId | Nosto | Targeting | Nosto sets up first party cookies in order to identify browsers between their visits and during their visit.  | Persistant | <https://help.nosto.com/manuals/nosto-cookies>  
  
Accept or block Cookies

Most browsers have cookies enabled by default but you are able to change your cookies settings, which are usually found in the 'options' or 'preferences' menu of your internet browser.

You can block any cookies from any website by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of some or all cookies. However, if you block all cookies you may not be able to access all or part of our Website. You can also use your browser settings to delete cookies. For more information about how to disable cookies in your browser please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

If you share the use of a computer, accepting or rejecting the use of cookies may affect all users of that computer.

If you would like more information about our privacy policy overall, please visit our dedicated [Privacy Policy](https://www.everything5pounds.com/en/privacy-cookies)

Last updated: 20 March 2019
